Collins Kigen

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Profile

I'm a full-stack software developer proficient in Python and JavaScript. I have two years of expertise developing back-end APIs with the Django Rest framework and front-end UIs with React. I strive to build and implement creative software solutions that enhance business productivity. I am enthusiastic in continuous learning and proactive in taking up tasks.

Employment History

Backend engineer, Giglab limited, Nairobi

JANUARY 2022 - MAY 2022

- I oversaw all aspects of the design and development of APIs using Python Django
- Creating the CI/CD pipeline for the back end of the product.
- I worked with my teammates to develop a highly reliable and maintainable code for the product
- I participated in code reviews with my teammates
- Some of the projects I worked on is Appetit, a recipe app where I was part of the back end team

Intern, International Centre of Insect Physiology and Ecology, Nairobi

OCTOBER 2021 - JANUARY 2022

 Underwent expert mentorship program where i was trained on Python, git, docker, hpc, bash machine learning and data science techniques

Software developer, Freelance/Self employed

JANUARY 2020 - PRESENT

- Worked on various projects on Python and JavaScript including
 - Cryo-bank API, a sample inventory app
 - Pa-pet an e-commerce pet store
 - Mama garage, a college website

Education

Biochemistry, Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology, Nairobi

SEPTEMBER 2015 - NOVEMBER 2019

Majored in bio informatics

Courses

Data Science with Python, Simplilearn

MARCH 2021 - MARCH 2022

References

References available upon request

Details

+254717591918 ckigen.k@gmail.com

Links

Portfolio website

Linkedin

GitHub

Skills

MongoDB

CSS

HTML5

Git

Python

Django rest framework

Docker

JavaScript

React

PostgresSQL

Bash Scripting

Hobbies

Chess Hiking